hello everyone
today we will do a quick GT:NH run
to get started, we build a small shelter with the basic storage and survival stuff
next we make a new room
where we can place our first steam machines
and once we get bigger steam machines
we can also build a couple of blast furnaces
this will allow us to produce the steel required for our low voltage workshop
which can be used to craft an electric blast furnace
to make the aluminium for the new MV machines
all of that progression is taking a lot of resources
which we are processing in the basement
where we automated raw mineral sorting and processing
to power all of that
we are using four railcraft boilers fueled with charcoal blocks made from the wood produced by a spruce bonsai farm
this setup will be enough for our additional blast furnaces
and the new HV machines which can be used to assemble the parts for a rocket
now that we have a rocket
we can take off to new far places, such as the moon
here we can find some rare materials that weren't abundant on earth
like Bauxite and neodymium
but most importantly
we can now move to the garden dimension, a builder's heaven
where there are no hostile creatures, and it's always sunny
the first thing we build here is a complete oil refinery
which will yield all sorts of products
after using those for our chemistry industry
we use the leftover to fuel our new factory
with that we can now power 16 blast furnaces and our new workshop equipped with all kinds of small machines
that will allow us to craft anything we could possibly want
and to quickly process hundreds of items at once
we also have a workshop section with some powerful multi blocks
the only issue left is to find a way of collecting enough raw materials
to do so, we tried a different approach
we did all sorts of weird rituals
until we found a way of gathering materials that is easier than flying into space
we make space rocks fly to us
that way we can easily collect valuable materials
without having to leave our base
to process all of those raw minerals
we built an ore processing plant right next to the meteor crashing site
next we do some further refinement in our chemical processing plant
and for those materials that still aren't ready for blast smelting
we have a place where can build longer refinement processing lines
starting from the platinum line
however as you can see it's not working
and the issue seems to be a lack of hydrogen
since we need a planetary amount
the only solution is to go back to space again
this time the target is the only place with enough hydrogen to satisfy our needs
Jupiter
to get the hydrogen, we build a space station equipped with a planetary gas siphon
and start slowly pumping the whole gaseous planet towards our base
with that, our platinum line is starting to work again
however platinum is not the only material that requires processing from a chain of machines
we also had to set up a processing line for monazite
to obtain samarium cerium and other rare earth elements
which we used to build a processing line for purifying naquadah
finally, we also had to build a processing line for netherite
to power all of those new machines
we are using only clean energy
starting from a geothermal plant that produces steam from underground heat
next to our heat pumping station
we also have a hydro electric plant
built on the slice of river that passes underneath our base
but our main source of energy are eight wind turbines
depending on wind strength
those can reach a power output peak of 560 kEU per tick
and if we fly higher
we can see the start of our compressed solar panel array
which should outgrow our wind farm
finally moving to the nether
we are also using some nuclear reactors
to power our ancient debris collection process
those things are needed to build machines capable of withstanding temperatures higher than the sun
such as our new fusion reactor
but one was not enough
so we made another one
and another one
and then we scale those one tier up
and we can use the old fusion reactors to boost our energy production
but the real technological progress is that we can now get into quantum computing
after building our first small quantum computer and a research station
we can start working on wetware circuits
powerful enough to control UHV tier machines
but what we are actually going to want is a UV crops synthesizer
which can be used to bait one of the best meteorites that can be achieved
rich of all of the rarest minerals that normally don't even spawn in nature
however while this is a great source of metals that we can't easily obtain by other means
it has two huge downsides
the first one is that summoning this meteor took the life of some sentient circuits
the second issue is that we have to physically dig it
block by block
to fix all those problems
and also get a better selection of collected minerals
we can move to our mega apiary
here we can beekeep some special breeds of bees
that produce some high quality honeycombs
from which we can extract all sorts of delicacies
such as electric motors
but there are still some materials we can't obtain easily from bees or meteors
like awakened draconium required for our next blast furnace upgrade
we could obtain it by gambling on a new species of bee
but since we aren't lobotomizing ourselves by grinding in a closed garden
we will simply catch the first vega B rocket passing by
and once we get air dropped onto the new planet
we can quickly proceed into digging a hole to its core
where we will be able to find small amounts of the needed material
with that we can craft the royal bed required for the mutagen gene driven mating process of the Drake bee
and as soon as it's ready
we can move it to the mega apiary
where it will quickly produce enough honeycombs to upgrade all of our volcanoes
but even with that upgrade
we still struggle keeping up with all of the blast smelting needed
so we opted for a mega blast furnace
the issue is that this giant machine will use a giant amount of energy
to keep up with that we built a couple of XL-plasma turbines
and while those managed to produce enough power
the amount of fuel used became a new issue
at first we tried to fix that by building more fusion reactors
but this solution couldn't really match our consumption
so we designed a more compact solution
a single giant reactor that can match hundreds of the smaller ones
that solution worked really well
until we realized that producing all of that plasma was using an amount of hydrogen bigger than Jupiter
and if the biggest planet of our solar system isn't enough
the only thing left to do is pump fluids from all over the galaxy
but building space stations all over the galaxy is too much of a chore
so we opted for a single giant space elevator in our base
equipped with a super powerful pump capable of suction in gases from the whole universe
but building this pump requires some really strong materials
leaving aside all of the neutronium and infinity
the real issue lies in the magnetic material required for the inner shaft of a motor powerful enough to spin such pump
tengam
just to catch a meteor with traces of it
we need an ion thruster jet
but since this is quite expensive
instead of throwing it away for a dozen of tengam ores
we shall put it on our new improvised mother ship
to push it to a new galaxy where tengam spawns naturally
and after a long voyage
we got our mothership in the correct area
now we can prepare a smaller shuttle
which can be used to land on a tengam rich planet
where we quickly build a powerful void miner
with that we can conclude our space adventure
and relocate to our base
where we can start working on the powerful space pumps
and it was then that we run for the first time into the infinit issue of not having enough infinity
to make one ingot of that material
we currently need 11 stacks of Infinity catalyst dust
which we are mainly collecting with space drones
however
not only the collection is still too slow even though we have multiple drones working on it
we are also low on diamonds and nether stars
not to mention all of the cosmic neutronium required
which will be a hard task even for our mega blast furnaces and freezers running at 100 million EU per tick each
to fix all of those issues there is only one solution
a dimensionally transcendent Plasma Forge
or dtpf for the homies
this giant structure will melt pure infinity out of infinity catalyst
completely removing the cost for neutronium and diamonds
but don't be fooled
while the energy cost looks low
it needs some excited dimensionally transcendent fuel
and this innocent bucket of exotic material is a super high energy cost concentrate of a huge collection of nuclear fusion products
to produce enough of this fuel
we had to build a dedicated processing plant
which of course was using more energy than we were producing
so we upgraded our power plant
but all of those things running on fusion products started to overwhelm our compact fusion reactors
throttling our whole base
it was clear that we were going to need more and more plasma
and the Mark III reactor technology wasn't going to do it
so we started working on a prototype of fusion reactor capable of achieving perfect overclock
with this structure
we can now quickly craft millions of buckets of plasma
for all of our needs
which means that we have enough fuel to run a second dtpf
this one will be equipped with Infinity Coils
and run on higher power settings
to quickly and cheaply craft all sort of things
like neutronium from iron
but the real game changer is that this machine will be able to craft tesseracts
while the main usage for those is to produce transcendent metal
what we are after is the energized tesseract technology
capable of wirelessly linking machines
making it super easy for our matter manipulator to easily copy paste our production lines
building all of that was quite resource intensive
so after building a water purification plant capable of producing subatomically perfected water
we finally obtained the last ingredient required for the most energy intensive machine of the modpack
capable of making unlimited dtpf fuel
the dimensionally transcendent plasma mixer
this machine has unlimited mixing power
or to better specify
the only limit is our power production
indeed as soon as we turn it on
in 5 seconds, it produced one day worth of dtpf fuel
and also used two days worth of energy backup
and that made us realize that we might have some major energy production issue
it was clear that we needed some better way of making energy
no matter how many more plasma turbines we will build
no matter what kind of exotic metal we use for the blades of our turbines
it won't be enough
and that's also because our Mark 4 fusion reactor barely keeps up with the plasma production with our current energy conversion rate
looking at the sky for a solution
we peeked at a fusion reactor which might be big enough
the only issue was figuring out a way of capturing all of that energy
we figured out we could achieve that by enclosing the sun in a sphere of mirrors
that will redirect all of its energy to our base
accomplishing such task was not easy
especially because placing so many mirrors at that scale required a precision which no normal motor could achieve
luckily using some tessaracts
we managed to create some four dimensional motors which were perfect for the task
and once the Dyson sphere was completed
we managed to produce 1/3 of a trillion EU per tick
since even superconductors couldn't move that much energy
we had to use laser pipes to focus all of that energy in light form
with that kind of power
we managed to push our DTPFs at the limits of the universe
synthesizing space time itself
with this revolutionary material
we managed to build motors and pistons strong enough to compress things into a black hole
and once we properly stabilized a black hole
we can use its gravitational field to compress whatever we want
thus we obtained unlimited amounts of super dense materials
such as eternal singularities
which we can now use for mundane tasks
such as showering or storage
one other usage for all of those singularities is the final tier of coils which will be with us for the rest of the game
eternal coils
with those we can unlock all of the dtpf recipes
and we shall start by making space time at 8 times the speed for 8 times less materials
meanwhile we can use our old hypogen dtpfs to passively produce Infinity
at the moderate speed of 4 million liters per hour
each with a recipe that uses only one Infinity catalyst for each stack of Infinity ingots
however that was also quickly draining all of our fuel
and the issue was that our fusion reactors couldn't produce the ingredients fast enough
it was obvious that we had to improve our fusion technology once again
so we started working on the final type of fusion coils
and after the initial examination of the crafting plan
between all of the missing ingredients
we noticed that once again
our platinum line is having trouble keeping up
this time we couldn't pinpoint a specific issue
this gigantic cluster of machines is just too convoluted and slow for our needs
so after quickly reanalyzing the design of our platline, looking for improvements
we realized we can just scratch all of that
and use force to quantum the platinum out of unrefined metal dusts
and there is our new platline
a single machine that can be speed up by simply tweaking the input power
and now that we are refining platinum at 100 times the speed
we can't help but want to improve our other processing lines
after quickly doing so
we realized that this incredible machine can also replace all of our bacterial vats
after reimagining all of our processing lines
the only thing missing for our new fusion reactor was dragon blood
now while hunting dragons is a nice activity to keep your body engaged
it's not a reliable source of dragon blood
considering our needs
even with the infinite world generation
we would still put this species at risk of extinction
looking for a solution we invited some friends over
they then proceeded into summoning a demon
who traded its heart for some emeralds
we used that to craft an infinity egg
capable of producing an infinite amount of dragon blood
with that, we finally managed to build our compact fusion reactor Mark 5 final type
and with all of that fusing power
our plasma fuel production skyrocketed
allowing for a huge expansion of our dtpf cluster
with so many plasma forges
we can now produce enough infinity, space time and shirabon to mass produce quantum circuits
the highest tier of circuit capable of controlling UXV machinery
and that means that we can now spam wireless energy hatches
now we can just press Ctrl C, Ctrl V and make our base grow exponentially
without having to connect any cable
however an exponential amount of new machines requires an exponential amount of extra energy production
and while building more Dyson Spheres doesn't require much effort
crafting all of the parts requires a lot of transcendent metal
currently we are blasting that material with the power of three Dyson spheres
but it seems to still be far from enough
and it was exactly when every hope was lost to darkness
that a new light brightened our blast's melting area
it was not our fusion reactor blowing up
but a forge sent directly from the gods
and in this gigantic machine
we found a module capable of quickly processing all of our transcendental materials
and to show the gods our gratitude
we decided to build the biggest pyramid ever in their honor
to do so we needed huge amounts of stone
and the best way of gathering it seems to be placing a whole planet inside something called eye of harmony
while crafting all of the parts for such a marvelous machine isn't too easy
putting everything together is the main issue
since we have no time to waste
we are going to shove the energy produced by six Dyson Spheres into our assembly lines to speed up the crafting process
and after not too much time
we managed to complete our first eye of harmony
that machine will take two hours to produce 240 millions units of stone dust
that sounds like a lot
but considering we already had 9 billions it's not
if we truly want to impress the gods
we have to improve our space time compression technology
to the point where our eye of harmony is capable of containing the deep♂dark
thus harnessing more than 1 billion stone dusts at once
however that won't fix the speed issue
if anything it will make it worse
so if we want the process to be done in a tolerable amount of time
we also have to improve our time dilation technology
doing so is no easy task
the first issue we noticed is the amount of infinity required
luckily, after 8 hours of working towards fully breaching dimensional boundaries, and with the help of a transdimensional alignment matrix
our dtpfs achieved full convergence
thus acquiring perfect overclock
that made our Infinity production skyrocket to 5 billions liters per hour
but this comes with a huge cost a lot of plasma fuel
so much that even a full tower of final type fusion reactors couldn't keep up with that
thanks god
his forge can be equipped with a plasma fabricator module which was just enough for our needs
with that, we finally managed to build our first eye of harmony
which however, was still too slow
we could speed it up with better time dilation field generators
but those cost dwarf matter
only produced by the eye of harmony itself
the only solution left was to overclock the machine
which means 4 times the energy for twice the speed
and that caused once again energy issues
this time the scale of the problem is huge
as large as the number of stars in the sky
since we built so many Dyson spheres
that there are no more stars to use
there was only one thing left to try, antimatter
after producing a decent amount of that stuff
we can slam it in the Slam to quickly charge up our batteries
all was left to do was to figure out the correct balance between antimatter production and eye of harmony overclocking
the correct solution turned out to be that we should just keep building more antimatter sequences
until our eye of harmony finally reached the gallifreyan tier
and of course, one was not enough
actually not even 20 eye of harmony were enough for our future projects
we needed more stone dust
and this approach was too slow
the solution we figured out was to compress an eye of harmony into an astral array fabricator
thus exponentially increasing production
and that reminded us that stone dust is not the only thing we are getting from this microverse
we are indeed getting a lot of raw stellar plasma mixture
which we can use to fuel and empower the gorgeous forge of the gods
by increasing the fuel we burn
we can indeed boost the power of its furnaces
but what really matters is that we are showing our devotion to the deities
helping us progress in our path of transcendence
and that reminded us that we should prepare our gift in a proper package
so after charging up an Error-tier battery
we started packaging our stone into an artificial universe storage cell
and only then we realized a fatal misunderstanding
we can't gift the greatest pyramid ever because we are constantly producing more of it
and since our production keeps growing exponentially
any gift would look like a joke compared to what we could do the day after
but after being lost in the labyrinth of our thoughts for a scary amount of time
we finally saw a light at the end of the tunnel
we don't have to make a single package
we can do a constant delivery
but of course
reaching the dimension beyond the stars will require a really strong portal
a star gate
the issue is that transcendent motors don't have the strength required to carry our gift
while space time motors don't have the extra dimensional capability to reach dimensions beyond our comprehension
we needed to design a new kind of motor
this time we started by mixing together the four basic substances of reality, obtaining primordial matter
with that and some other rather complicated materials
we create some universium nanites
then we move from the nanite forge to the implosion compressor
where we blow those nanites inside some condensed stelar plasma mixture magneto hydrodynamically constraining it
that material will be the foundation of our new motors
but we need something to properly mold such impossible fluid
and quantum forcing some eternity out of primordial matter seems to do the trick
but to properly meld everything together
we had to use an implosion compressor
and add some advanced technology to contain the new material
and after putting everything together
we finally obtained a motor strong enough for the delivery of the biggest ever growing pyramid
all was left to do was to produce enough of those motors
so we had to do several upgrades to our factory
we started by checking if our fusion tower was good enough
then we added more astral arrays to our eyes of harmony
next we built more assembly lines
more assembly lines
and after going through every single side quest we were given
we are finally ready to defeat the final boss
to do so we first merge all of our eyes of harmony into a single one with 1000 Astral arrays
then we use a draconic reactor configuration that should not be seen by naked mortal eyes
to produce enough chaos shards to get a couple of singularity crafting storages
so that we can one step craft the Stargate
finally, we use the secret technique of the double matter manipulator to complete the final challenge
and exactly when we thought we were done
we realized that the real value here is not in the giant pile of stone dust
but in the machines we built along the way
so following the random comments coming from whatever place this gate leads to
we decided to take one extra step and make 10 more star gates
and after one week of pushing our factory at the limits of the computation capacity of the simulation we call reality
we finally managed to complete the task
and with that, I think our factory is now good enough to keep growing on its own
so we can fly away to the next adventure
bye bye
大家好
今天我们要速通GTNH
首先，我们建一个有基本的储物和生存用品的小庇护所
接下来我们做一个新房间
在那里我们可以放置第一台蒸汽机器
一旦我们有了更大的蒸汽机器
我们还可以建几个砖高炉
这将使我们能够生产 LV 车间所需的钢材
这些钢材可以用来制造一个电高炉
用来给新的 MV 机器制造铝
所有这些进展需要大量的资源
而我们正在地下室处理它们
我们在这自动化原矿分拣和加工
为了给这一切供能
我们使用四个RC锅炉，用云杉木农场
生产的木材制成的木炭块作为燃料
这个装置对我们额外的高炉
和能够用于组装火箭零件的新HV机器来说足够了
既然我们有了火箭
我们可以飞到新的地方，比如月球
我们可以在这里找到一些地球上比较稀少的矿物
像铝土矿和钕
但最重要的是
我们现在可以搬进"花园维度"，一个建筑师的天堂
那里没有敌对的生物，总是阳光明媚
我们首先要建的是一个完整的炼油厂
用于产出各类化工产品
在把这些产品投入化工生产后
我们把剩余的产物用来给新工厂供能
有了这些，我们现在可以驱动 16 座高炉
还有一整间装满各种小型机器的新车间
这样我们几乎想做什么都能做出来了
为了一次性高速处理上百个物品
车间里还有一块摆满了各种强力多方块机器的区域
唯一剩下的问题是收集到足够的原材料
为此，我们尝试了不同的方法
我们做了各种稀奇古怪的"仪式"
直到我们找到了一种比亲自飞到太空还要轻松的收集方式
我们让太空里的石头自己飞过来
这样我们可以很容易地收集到有价值的材料
而且完全不用离开基地
为了处理这些粗矿
我们就在陨石坠落点旁边建了一座矿石处理工厂
接着再送到化工厂里做进一步的精炼
而对于那些还不适合丢进高炉冶炼的材料
我们还有一片地方可以搭建更长的精炼产线
从铂产线开始
不过如你所见，它现在并不在工作
看起来问题是氢气不够
毕竟我们需要的是行星级的用量
唯一的办法就是再上一次太空
这次的目标，是唯一能提供足够氢气来满足我们需求的地方
木星
为了得到氢气，我们建了一座装有行星气体钻机的空间站
慢慢把整颗气态行星抽到我们的基地
这样一来，我们的铂产线又开始运转起来了
不过，需要整条生产线来处理的可不止铂这一种材料
我们还得搭一条独居石处理线
用它来提炼钐、铈以及其他稀土元素
这些稀土元素又用于建造硅岩净化处理线
最后，我们还必须为下界合金建造一条处理线
为了给这一大堆新机器供电
我们只使用清洁能源
先是靠深地热泵，用地下热量来产蒸汽
在热泵旁边
我们还有一个水力发电厂
就修在穿过基地下方的那条河上
不过，我们的主力电源是八台风力涡轮机
输出则要看风力强弱
这些最多能做到 560 kEU/t 的峰值输出
如果我们飞得更高
就能看到我们压缩太阳能板阵列中建好的第一台设备
它以后的规模应该会超过风电场
最后我们来到下界
在那儿我们也用上了几座核反应堆
给远古残骸的采集供能
远古残骸是用来造"能承受比太阳
还高温度的机器"的关键材料
比如我们新的聚变反应堆
但只造一台根本不够
所以我们又做了一台
双来一台
叒来一台
然后再把它们都提升一个等级
旧的聚变堆还能拿来增加发电量
不过真正的技术飞跃是我们终于可以踏入量子计算领域了
在造出第一台小型量子计算机和研究站之后
我们就可以着手研究湿件电路了
强到足以控制 UHV 电压的机器
但我们真正想要的是一台UV 作物合成机
它可以"钓"出游戏里能弄到的顶级陨石之一
里面有很多极其稀有、不会自然生成的矿石
尽管这是获得其他方式难以取得的金属的好方法
但它也有两个非常致命的缺点
第一，召唤这块陨石的时候，会牺牲几块有知觉的电路
第二，这玩意儿得我们自己上手挖
一格一格地挖
想把这些问题一起解决
顺便把产出的矿物搭配也优化一下
该巨型工业蜂箱出场了
在这里我们可以养一些特殊品种的蜜蜂
它们会产出各种高品质蜂巢
我们可以从中提取各种美味佳肴
比如电动马达
不过有些材料，靠蜜蜂和陨石依然不太好搞到
比如下一次高炉升级要用的觉醒龙锭
理论上我们可以搏一搏杂交出新蜜蜂品种
但我们又不打算在封闭花园里把自己无脑肝成植物人
我们赶一班路过的前往织女一的火箭就行
被空投到那颗新星球上之后
我们快速下挖，直至星核
在那附近就能找到少量我们需要的材料
拿这些材料就能做出皇家蜂床
用来完成恶龙蜂那套靠诱变基因驱动的繁殖流程
东西一旦做好
我们立刻把它放入巨型工业蜂箱
很快就能产出一大批蜂巢，把我们所有的炽焱高炉统统升级
可就算有了这些升级
想跟上高炉冶炼的需求还是有点吃力
所以我们干脆上一个巨型高炉
问题是，这玩意儿吃电也巨离谱
为了喂饱它，我们造了几台特大等离子涡轮
这些机器的发电量倒是堪堪够用
但消耗的燃料量又变成新的大坑
一开始我们想多造点聚变堆把问题糊过去
但这套方案还是跟不上我们恐怖的用电量
于是我们又设计了一版紧凑的方案
一台顶得上几百台小号反应堆的巨型反应堆
一开始效果确实相当不错
直到我们发现，为了产出这么多等离子
消耗的氢气量已经比一整颗木星还多
要是连太阳系里最大的行星都不够榨
那就只能去其他星系抽流体了
可在其他星系建空间站，这工作量也太离谱了
于是我们选择在基地里竖一根巨型太空电梯
加一台超级抽气泵，能把整个宇宙的气体都往这边吸
不过要造这玩意儿，需要的材料强度离谱
先不提那些中子、无尽之类的材料
真正卡人的，是能让这台泵转起来的马达内轴用的磁性材料
——纯镃
光是要抓一块带点纯镃的陨石
我们就得先造一台离子推进喷口
但因为那东西真的很贵
与其为了一些纯镃矿就扔掉这个喷口
那不如直接把它装到一艘我们临时凑出来的母舰上
把整艘母舰推进到一个能自然生成纯镃的新星系去
在太空里漂泊了好一阵之后
我们总算把母舰开到了目标星域
接下来就可以准备一艘小型穿梭机
坐它降落到一颗纯镃储量丰富的行星上
在那里快速架一台高配虚空采矿厂
搞定这些之后，这一趟太空冒险就可以收尾了
然后我们打道回府
回到基地，就能正式开工造那台真正的宇宙级气泵
就在此时，我们第一次遇到无尽的"无尽锭不够用"的问题
现在要做出一块无尽锭
光是无尽催化剂粉就要用掉 11 组
这些主要是靠各种太空无人机一点点搬回来的
然而
就算已经派了好几架无人机在干，收集速度还是太慢
我们手上的钻石和下界之星也库存见底
更别提还要准备一大堆宇宙中子态素
就算我们那几座巨高炉和冷冻机吃一亿 EU/t
这任务还是难到爆炸
要把这些问题一网打尽，其实只有一个解法
那就是——超维度等离子锻炉
或者简称 DTPF
这座庞然大物可以把无尽催化剂直接熔成无尽
这样做就完全不用消耗中子和钻石了
不过别被表面数据骗了
从配方上看，它本身吃电其实不算多
关键是它需要激发的超维度燃料
这一小桶看起来人畜无害的异星催化剂
是把一大堆能量密度高得离谱的核聚变产物经浓缩得到的
为了生产出足够多这种燃料
我们不得不专门给它建一整座加工厂
而这工厂自己吃的电，当然是比整个基地发的电还多
于是我们只好再把整个发电系统升级一轮
不过所有这些靠聚变产物运转的玩意儿
已经快把那几台紧凑型聚变堆压垮了
限制了我们整个基地的产能
很明显，接下来我们只会需要越来越多的等离子体
而三阶反应堆已经完全撑不住了
所以我们开始研究一台可以实现完美超频的聚变原型机
有了这台机器后
我们现在可以非常快地造出几百万桶等离子体
基本能满足我们的需求了
这也意味着，燃料多到可以再养活第二台 DTPF 了
这一台会装上无尽线圈
并以更高功率运行
用来又快又省地合成各种材料
比如直接把普通铁炼成中子
但真正让游戏质变的是，这机器能直接做超立方体
尽管超立方体的主要用途是做超时空金属
不过我们真正看上的是充能超立方体解锁的科技
它可以在机器之间建立无线链接
让物质操纵者复制粘贴整条产线
变得跟按 Ctrl+C／Ctrl+V 一样简单
把这一整套系统堆出来，资源消耗自然是夸张到不行
所以我们又建了一座净水厂，能生产出亚原子级纯净水
这才终于凑齐了整合包里那台
最吃电力的机器所需要的最后一种材料
那台机器可以源源不断地制造 DTPF 用的燃料
它名叫超维度等离子搅拌机
理论上这玩意儿的混合能力是没有上限的
更确切地说
唯一的上限是我们能发多少电
实际上，这东西一旦开机
不到 5 秒就搅出了够 DTPF 用一整天的燃料
顺手把我们两天份的电力储备一口气榨干
于是我们不得不承认：
在发电这一块，大抵是有严重问题的
很明显，我们必须找一套更靠谱的发电方案
无论再多造多少台等离子涡轮
更别提给涡轮叶片换上多离谱的稀有金属
最终都还是完全不够看
再加上以现在这点能量转换效率，
就连四阶聚变堆都几乎跟不上等离子体的产量
于是我们只好抬头寻找答案
我们一眼瞟见一个可能够大的聚变反应堆
唯一的问题是想办法把那些能量全收集下来
我们想到可以通过用球状排列的镜子包住太阳来实现这一点
把太阳辐射出的能量全部反射到我们的基地
要做到这件事当然一点也不轻松
尤其是在那种尺度下摆这么多镜子
需要普通马达根本做不到的精度
好在我们手里还有超立方体可以用
借助它们搞出了几台"四维马达"，刚好能胜任这活
等整套戴森球结构封装完成之后
我们的发电量直接拉到三千多亿 EU/t
但这么大的功率，就连超导线都扛不住
我们只好用激光管道，把所有能量转成光来传输
有了这样的发电量之后
我们的 DTPF 终于可以被推到接近"宇宙极限"的强度
甚至可以直接合成时空本身
有了这种划时代的新材料
我们造出了"强到能把东西压成黑洞"的马达和活塞
等黑洞被稳定下来之后
我们就能利用它的引力场，压任何想压的东西
于是我们就有了几乎无限量的超高密度物质
比如永恒奇点
现在这种东西多到可以拿来完成每日任务
比如用来冲澡或者储存
当然，它们最关键的用途是做
之后游戏会一直用到的最高级线圈
永恒线圈
有了这些线圈，我们就能解锁所有 DTPF 的配方
先从时空物质开刀，做到八倍速度
材料消耗只有原来的八分之一
与此同时，我们用旧的海珀珍 DTPF 被动生产无尽
速度也不算慢，大概是每小时四百万桶左右
而配方里每一组无尽锭只要用一个无尽催化剂
不过这样会很快把我们的燃料用完
问题在于聚变堆根本来不及产出这些燃料需要的前置材料
很明显，聚变技术还得再往上推一档
于是我们开始研究最终版本的聚变线圈
合成计划里粗略看了一圈之后
在那一长串缺的材料里面
我们又一次发现——
铂处理的速度跟不上需求
但这次我们无法确定是哪一台机器掉链子
整片机器群无比复杂的同时，效率还跟不上现在的需求
于是我们把整条铂处理的流程重新过了一遍
想看看哪里还能提速
结果发现：与其优化，不如全拆了重来
直接上量子科技，从一堆未精炼的金属粉里硬"抖"出铂
这就是我们新的铂处理产线
只靠一台机器，只要灌入电力就能一直往上提速
现在铂的精炼速度是以前的一百倍
我们自然也忍不住想顺手把其他几条产线也一并优化
简单折腾一圈之后
我们才发现这台牛逼的机器甚至
可以把所有的细菌培养缸都给淘汰掉
在彻底重构完我们所有的产线之后
新的聚变反应堆只还缺最后一种材料：龙血
打龙本身倒是个不错的运动项目
但那绝对算不上龙血的稳定来源
尤其是考虑到我们这种夸张的用量
即使是有无限生成的世界
我们还是会让它濒临灭绝
为了解决这个问题，我们叫了几位朋友过来商量对策
结果商量变成了恶魔召唤
那只恶魔用自己的心脏跟我们交易了些绿宝石
我们则用这东西做出了一个无限之蛋
这个蛋可以源源不断地给我们提供龙血
有了稳定的龙血供应
我们终于把紧凑型聚变堆升级到 MK-V 最终版
在这样离谱的聚变能力加持下
等离子燃料的产量直接起飞
这也让我们有资本把整片 DTPF 集群疯狂扩容
在这么多台等离子锻炉同时开工的情况下
我们现在能量产用来批量做量子电路的无尽时空和调律源金
量子电路是用来控制 UXV 机器的最高阶电路
这也意味着我们现在可以到处安装无线能量仓
现在我们只需要按下 Ctrl+C、Ctrl+V，基地就开始指数级长大
而且还不用到处拉电线
不过机器数量指数增长，发电量也得跟着指数级翻倍
虽然再多造几个戴森球倒也不算多麻烦
但做戴森球用的那些零件需要很多超时空金属
现在我们在"用了三套戴森球发电量的高炉"里烧这种金属
结果看下来，还是远远不够用
就在我们快要彻底绝望、感觉一切都陷入黑暗的时候
熔炼区域里突然亮起了一道全新的光
那并不是我们的聚变堆要炸了
而是一座由诸神亲手赐下的巨型锻炉
在这台巨无霸机器里
我们找到一个能把所有高阶材料
统统高速处理完的专用模块
为了向诸神表达我们的感谢
我们决定亲手建一座史上最大的金字塔来敬仰他们
要搞出那座金字塔，我们需要海量的石头
最省事的收集方式是把整颗星球
塞进一台叫鸿蒙之眼的机器里
当然，这么逆天的机器，它要的零件就已经够折腾了
真正麻烦的是把所有东西组装在一起的那一步
因为我们没有时间可供挥霍
我们要把六套戴森球的发电量全塞进装配线里
把制造速度拉满
没过多久
第一台鸿蒙之眼总算是建成了
这台机器两个小时就能生产两亿四千万单位的石头粉
那听起来好像已经很多了
但考虑到我们一开始就已经攒了九十多亿，其实也就那回事
如果我们真想惊艳诸神
我们得升级自己的时空压缩技术
直到鸿蒙之眼的内部空间大到能整个塞下漆黑世界
这样一来，就能一次性榨出超过十亿单位的石头粉
不过，这并不能解决速度问题
说不定还会让问题变得更严重
所以如果我们想让这个流程在可以接受的时间内完成的话
我们还得继续升级自己的时间膨胀技术
想做到这一点可一点都不轻松
我们发现的第一个问题是需要的夸张的无尽数量
好在经过八个小时的不断运行，彻底打穿维度边界
再加上跨维度对齐矩阵的加持
我们的 DTPF 终于实现了完全收敛
由此解锁了完美超频
于是我们的无尽产量直接暴涨到每小时五十亿桶
但代价是等离子燃料的巨量消耗
多到就算一整塔的终极聚变堆全开，照样跟不上这消耗速度
感谢诸神
它的煅炉可以装一个等离子制造模块
刚好能补上我们燃料上的窟窿
有了这套配置，我们终于造出了第一台鸿蒙之眼
不过它还是太慢了
理论上可以靠更高级的时间膨胀场发生器给它提速
但那玩意儿要吃矮星物质
而矮星物质又只能靠鸿蒙之眼自己产
唯一的办法是把机器超频
也就是用四倍的能耗，换来两倍的速度
这再一次导致能源问题
而且这次的规模大得离谱
大到几乎和天上星星的数量一个量级
毕竟我们已经造了这么多戴森球
都快把能用的恒星用光了
最后只剩一个方向可试——
反物质
把反物质产量堆到一个像样的水平后
就把它们塞进湮灭矩阵，一口气把电池充满
接下来就是在"反物质产量"和"鸿蒙之眼的超频程度"之间
找一个合适的平衡点
答案其实很直接，继续堆更多反物质就对了
一直堆到鸿蒙之眼升到鸿蒙层级
当然，造一台肯定不够
说实话，就算二十台鸿蒙之眼，对后面的计划也远远不够
我们还需要更多石头粉
可照现在这套做法，还是太慢
我们的方案是把一台鸿蒙之眼压缩成一个星阵
这样产能就能呈指数级飙升
同时也提醒了我们：从这个微宇宙里拿到的不止石头粉一种
我们还会获得大量浓缩原始恒星等离子体混合物
这些都能拿去给诸神之锻炉供能
只要把燃料投入继续拉满
它的熔炉功率就能再往上推
更关键的是，这是在向诸神展现我们的诚意
也能帮助我们在这条"超凡"路上继续前进
这也提醒我们：礼物要打包得体，才能拿得出手
在把一个"Error 级"电池充满后
我们把这些石头打包进人造宇宙存储元件
直到这一步我们才反应到：我们有个致命的理解错误
我们没法献上"这史上最大的金字塔"
因为我们的工厂还在不断继续产出更多石头
而且产能还在指数级往上飙
今天送出去的规模，与明后天一比就像个笑话
在被自己之前的想法困了好久之后
我们总算看到了一点曙光
我们不必做一个"一次性礼包"
改成持续投递就行
但是当然
想把东西送到星辰之外的那个维度
需要一扇非常强力的传送门
也就是星门
问题在于，"超时空马达"无法承载我们这份礼物
而"时空马达"又缺少跨越更高维度的能力，根本到不了那边
所以我们得另做一种全新的马达
这次从"把现实的四种基本物质混在一起"开始
合成出本源物质
然后再加上一些相当复杂的材料
我们做出了一批宇宙素纳米蜂群
我们把它从从纳米锻炉搬到聚爆压缩机
我们在这里把纳米蜂群压缩成磁流体约束恒星物质
这种材料将是我们新马达的基础
但我们还缺一些东西才把这种"不可能的流体"彻底定型
对本源物质进行量子操控，析出永恒物质，就能解决这个问题
不过要把全部材料彻底融合
还得借助聚爆压缩机
并加上一些高级技术来收容这份新材料
把整套工序跑完之后
我们终于造出了一种强度足够高、
可以运输这座越长越大的巨型金字塔的新马达
接下来就是把这种马达量产出来
于是我们又对工厂进行了一轮升级改造
先是检查我们的聚变塔是否足够好
然后给鸿蒙之眼加装更多的星阵
接着再堆更多的装配线
继续给鸿蒙之眼叠星阵
再多上几条装配线
（字幕已阵亡）
把一路上给到的支线全都做完之后
我们总算准备好去打最终 Boss 了
为此，先把所有鸿蒙之眼合并成一台，堆到 1000 个星阵的规格
再用上一套凡胎肉眼无法直视的
龙之研究反应堆配置
刷出足量的混沌碎片
做出几个奇点合成存储器
这样就能一口气把星门直接合成出来
最后再开秘技：双持物质操纵者完成最终挑战
正当我们以为彻底搞定的时候
才发现真正有价值的并不是那一大堆石头粉
而是我们一路建起来的机器们
于是顺着星门另一头飘来的评论
决定更进一步——再造 10 座星门
把这个所谓“现实”的模拟世界算力榨到极限
又连续干了整整一周之后
这项任务终于宣告完成
到这一步，我觉得这座工厂已经强到可以自己继续成长了
那我们也可以放心奔赴下一段冒险了
拜拜
（*湿件电路）
（在neta量子操纵者的名字quantum force transfomer）